{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cables has the highest data transmission speed?",
            "answer": "Optical fibre cable",
            "other_options": [
                "Twisted-pair cable",
                "Telephone line",
                "Coaxial cable"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 62.5,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following will be assigned by a \n manufacturer when a network interface card is produced?",
            "answer": "MAC address",
            "other_options": [
                "URL",
                "IP address",
                "Domain name"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 52.734375,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following technology is NOT applied in wireless communications?",
            "answer": "Ultraviolet",
            "other_options": [
                "Bluetooth",
                "Infra-red",
                "Microwave"
            ],
            "feedback": "So, tell me how do you communicate with ultraviolet?",
            "weight": 93.75,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements about dial-up connection is correct?",
            "answer": "It covers a wider area than broadband connections.",
            "other_options": [
                "Its maximum transmission speed is 256 Kbps.",
                "A switch is needed to set up a dial-up connection.",
                "It is the most stable way to connect to the Internet nowadays."
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 52.734375,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements about LAN is correct?",
            "answer": "It can be wired or wireless network.",
            "other_options": [
                "It limits the number of computer to 10.",
                "It must have at least 1 server.",
                "It can interconnect all the computers in a community."
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 62.5,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a communication protocol?",
            "answer": "ISP",
            "other_options": [
                "POP",
                "TCP",
                "IP"
            ],
            "feedback": "POP (POP3): Post Office Protocol v3 \n TCP: Transmission Control Protocol \n IP: Internet Protocol \n ISP: Internet Service Provider, NOT a protocol.",
            "weight": 140.625,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following could NOT be a top-level domain name?",
            "answer": ".htm",
            "other_options": [
                ".org",
                ".hk",
                ".net"
            ],
            "feedback": ".htm is a file extension.",
            "weight": 70.3125,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following types of communication requires real-time interaction?",
            "answer": "Video conferencing",
            "other_options": [
                "Newsgroup",
                "E-mail",
                "Guestbook"
            ],
            "feedback": "Video conferencing require real-time communication.",
            "weight": 46.875,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following kinds of software CANNOT be used for communication?",
            "answer": "Desktop publishing",
            "other_options": [
                "Instant messaging",
                "Video conferencing",
                "Web browser"
            ],
            "feedback": "How can you communicate with a desktop publishing software?",
            "weight": 93.75,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "What does URL stand for?",
            "answer": "Uniform Resource Locator",
            "other_options": [
                "Uniform Resource Location",
                "Unique Resource Locator",
                "Unique Resource Location"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 140.625,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "IPv6 address has ___ .",
            "answer": "128 bits",
            "other_options": [
                "32 bits",
                "32 bytes",
                "128 bytes"
            ],
            "feedback": "An IPv6 address include 32 heximal digits.",
            "weight": 70.3125,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following items does NOT exist?",
            "answer": "CD+R",
            "other_options": [
                "CD-R",
                "DVD-R",
                "DVD+R"
            ],
            "feedback": "I guess your brain does NOT exist.",
            "weight": 125,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of portable storage device?",
            "answer": "DDR2 RAM",
            "other_options": [
                "Memory Stick",
                "SD card",
                "CompactFlash card"
            ],
            "feedback": "RAM is installed inside the computer.",
            "weight": 35.15625,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of a USB flash drive?",
            "answer": "Sequential access",
            "other_options": [
                "Portable",
                "Less susceptible to magnetic interference",
                "Lower power consumption"
            ],
            "feedback": "USB does not access data in a predetermined, ordered sequence.",
            "weight": 46.875,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a secondary storage device?",
            "answer": "ROM",
            "other_options": [
                "Floppy disk",
                "Hard disk",
                "SD card"
            ],
            "feedback": "ROM is installed inside the computer.",
            "weight": 52.734375,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following does NOT use direct access?",
            "answer": "Magnetic tape drive",
            "other_options": [
                "Memory card",
                "RAM",
                "USB"
            ],
            "feedback": "A tape drive is required to read magnetic tape drive",
            "weight": 140.625,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following tasks is NOT performed by an operating system?",
            "answer": "Word processing",
            "other_options": [
                "Device configuration",
                "Memory management",
                "File management",
                "Account management",
                "Auditing",
                "User interface"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 93.75,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the function of disk defragmenter?",
            "answer": "Reorganize the data into a better use of space.",
            "other_options": [
                "Format a hard disk.",
                "Back up data in a hard disk.",
                "Scan the hard disk and search for computer viruses."
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 158.203125,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT open source software?",
            "answer": "Internet Explorer",
            "other_options": [
                "Fedora Linux",
                "OpenOffice.org",
                "Apache HTTP Server"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 23.4375,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of communication software?",
            "answer": "Web authoring software",
            "other_options": [
                "Instant messaging software",
                "Web browser",
                "FTP program"
            ],
            "feedback": "Web authoring software is a type of desktop publishing tool.",
            "weight": 93.75,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of utility program does WinZip belong to?",
            "answer": "File compression utility",
            "other_options": [
                "Disk defragmenter",
                "System monitoring software",
                "File manager"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 140.625,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "DOS is a ___________________________ operating system.",
            "answer": "single-user and single-tasking",
            "other_options": [
                "single-user and multi-tasking ",
                "multi-user and single-tasking",
                "multi-user and multi-tasking"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 187.5,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following types of buses is used \n to carry data between different hardware components?",
            "answer": "Data bus",
            "other_options": [
                "Address bus",
                "IRQ bus",
                "Control bus"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 125,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements about RAM is true?",
            "answer": "RAM is volatile.",
            "other_options": [
                "Many computers are installed with at least 2 TB RAM nowadays.",
                "There are more ROM than RAM in a PC."
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 46.875,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following sequences of a machine cycle is correct?",
            "answer": "Fetch-Decode-Execute",
            "other_options": [
                "Decode-Fetch-Execute",
                "Decode-Execute-Fetch",
                "Fetch-Execute-Decode"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 79.1015625,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following registers contains a number of flag bits?",
            "answer": "SR",
            "other_options": [
                "IR",
                "MAR",
                "MDR"
            ],
            "feedback": "Status Register (SR) contains information about the state of the processor.",
            "weight": 46.875,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following register stores an address?",
            "answer": "PC",
            "other_options": [
                "IR",
                "ACC",
                "SR"
            ],
            "feedback": "Program Counter (PC) stores the address of the instruction will be executed next.",
            "weight": 70.3125,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a valid IPv6 address?",
            "answer": "2001:0db8:85a3:0000:0000:8a2e:0370:7334",
            "other_options": [
                "192.168.0.1",
                "10.120.224.250",
                "A0:FF:B3:45:10:2C"
            ],
            "feedback": "An IPv6 address include 32 heximal digits.",
            "weight": 62.5,
            "time_limit": 20
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following storage media is \n most suitable for a backup of 500GB data?",
            "answer": "Magnetic tape",
            "other_options": [
                "CD-R",
                "BLU-RAY disc",
                "USB"
            ],
            "feedback": "Magnetic tape is suitable for backup, can store up to 500GB, and most importantly, its price is affordable.",
            "weight": 52.734375,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is NOT used in a WAN?",
            "answer": "WIFI",
            "other_options": [
                "Satellites",
                "Optical fibre",
                "Telephone lines"
            ],
            "feedback": "WIFI is used in LAN (Local Area Network).",
            "weight": 105.46875,
            "time_limit": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following wireless technology supports longest distance?",
            "answer": "WIFI",
            "other_options": [
                "NFC",
                "RFID",
                "Bluetooth"
            ],
            "feedback": "",
            "weight": 35.15625,
            "time_limit": 15
        }
    ]
}